<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?><Search><pages Count="48"><page Index="1" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[AUTOMOTIVE. DIESEL. MOTORCYCLE. COLLISION REPAIR. NASCAR. MARINE. THE CHOICE IS YOURS!CHOSEN BY INDUSTRY. READY TO WORK.TECHNICIAN TRAINING FOR THE TRANSPORTATION INDUSTRY]]></page><page Index="2" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[UTI consistently graduates and places more technicians in the transportation industry than any other school in the country.]]></page><page Index="3" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Why choose UTI? Because the industry does.The world’s leading manufacturers trust UTI to train their technicians. Only UTI has teamed up with manufacturers of more than 30 top brands to provide technician training based on their own factory training programs. Together, UTI and these manufacturers have invested millions of dollars to ensure on-campus labs are equipped with the latest vehicles, equipment, tools and training aids.UTI’s instructors are experienced professionals with industry certifications and credentials plus real world experience. They know how to teach the way youwant to learn. As a result, you havethe opportunity to earn manufacturer certifications and credentials that are extremely valuable to future employers, and as a UTI graduate, you’re ready to work.As a respected leader in technician training for 50 years, UTI graduates more technicians than any other school in the country. And, our industry relationships are one of the reasons that 4 out of 5 of our graduates find employment in their fields of study.*The best manufacturers in the world choose UTI. Shouldn’t you?Number of manufacturer relationships UTI has with world-famous brandsUniversal Technical Institute, Inc. (UTI) offers specialized technical education programs under the banner of several well- known brands, including Universal Technical Institute, Motorcycle Mechanics Institute and Marine Mechanics Institute (MMI), and NASCAR Technical Institute.Approximately 9,900 of the 10,600 UTI graduates in 2013 were available for employment. At the time of reporting, approximately 8,700 were employed within one year of their graduation date, for a total of 88%. UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.INDUSTRY RELATIONSHIPSAcuraBMWBuickCadillac ChevroletFordGMCHondaInfinitiLexusLincoln Mercedes-Benz MININASCAR Nissan Porsche Scion Toyota VolvoCummins Freightliner International Peterbilt Western StarBMW Motorrad Harley-Davidson Honda Kawasaki SuzukiYamahaHonda Marine Mercury Marine Suzuki Marine Volvo Penta Yamaha Marine3MAxaltaCCCChiefI-CARLincoln Electric SATASnap-onCOLLISION REPAIR MARINE MOTORCYCLE DIESEL AUTOMOTIVE]]></page><page Index="4" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[CONTENTS04 Automotive Technician Training 06 Power & Performance08 Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training09 BMW FastTrack & STEP10 Ford FACT11 General Motors Technician Career Training12 Honda PACT13 Mercedes-Benz ELITE START & ADVANCED14 MINI STEP15 Nissan NATT16 Porsche PTAP17 Toyota TPAT18 Volvo SAFE19 Motorsports Industry Alliances20 NASCAR Technical Institute22 Diesel Technician Training24 Cummins Engines & Power Generation25 Daimler Finish First26 International ITEP27 Peterbilt Technician Institute28 Collision Repair and Refinish Technology 30 Motorcycle Mechanics Institute32 BMW Motorrad33 Harley-Davidson34 Honda Motorcycle35 Kawasaki36 Suzuki37 Yamaha38 Marine Mechanics Institute41 UTI Gets You Ready to Work42 Your Best Choice43 Scholarships44 Support and FAQs45 Campus Locationsffffff]]></page><page Index="5" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[GREAT RELATIONSHIPS = GREAT CAREERSWHY UTI?BRAND & REPUTATIONGraduating from a school with a quality reputation is important. As a leading provider of technician training, UTI has graduated more than 190,000 technicians and has been in business for 50 years.RELATIONSHIPS WITH THE INDUSTRYThe companies that work with UTI do so for a reason: They trust UTI to train the techniciansthat they employ. Many of UTI’s manufacturer- supported and branded programs are not available at any other school.FOCUSED AND ACCELERATED TRAININGWe teach what industry says matters most. Youcan complete an entry-level technician programin about a year, add manufacturer training and graduate in as little as 18 months. Our auto, diesel and collision repair training programs are accredited by the National Automotive Technicians Education Foundation (NATEF),** a division of the National Institute for Automotive Service Excellence (ASE). Graduates are well prepared to complete ASE examinations and can substitute our training forone of the two years of work experience required to become ASE Certiied.CERTIFIED, EXPERIENCED &CARING INSTRUCTORSAll of our instructors have years of experience working as technicians in the ield. They are certiied and credentialed in their areas of expertise and have a genuine interest in your success.LATEST TECHNOLOGY & EQUIPMENTOur industry relationships mean you will be learning the most current technology, hands-on, in labs outitted by our industry partners for your success.DIRECT CONNECTIONS TO A GREAT CAREEROur Employment Services team will bring our industry connections directly to you before you graduate. They will work with you to help develop your résumé and hone your interviewing skills. We will help you ind your irst job and assist you in your employment needs after you graduate through access to our alumni community, UTI Connect.View our complete list of manufacturer relationships at UTI.eduUTI / INDUSTRY RELATIONSHIPS 03Craig Jackson, UTI BMW STEP Graduate, on the job as Technical Support EngineerUTI GRADS ARE HIRED IN THEIR FIELDS OF STUDY.Approximately 9,900 of the 10,600 UTI graduates in 2013 were available for employment. At the time of reporting, approximately 8,700 were employed within one year of their graduation date, for a total of 88%.UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.Not all programs are NATEF accredited]]></page><page Index="6" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[fAUTOMOTIVEfff]]></page><page Index="7" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[AUTOMOTIVETECHNICIANTRAININGCOURSE LENGTH: 51 WEEKSPROGRAM LOCATIONS: AZ, CA,3 FL, IL, MA, NC,4 PA,TXIn UTI’s Automotive Technology program, you’ll learn how to diagnose, maintain and repair domestic and foreign automobiles.You will also ind out how to troubleshoot problems of all kinds, using the latest engine analyzers, handheld scanners and other computerized diagnostic equipment. You’ll learn everything from basic engine systems to computerized fuel injection, anti-lock brakes, computerized engine controls and much more.ACCREDITEDUTI’s Automotive Technology program is accredited by the National Automotive Technicians Education Foundation (NATEF), a division of the National Institute for Automotive Service Excellence (ASE).1Not all programs are NATEF accredited.INDUSTRY RELATIONSHIPSAcura LincolnBMW Mercedes-Benz Buick MINICadillac NASCAR Chevrolet NissanFord PorscheGMC ToyotaHonda ScionIniniti VolvoLexusYOUR COURSES WILL INCLUDE:Automotive Engines & Repair Professional Service Writing Automotive Power Trains BrakesElectronic Technology Climate ControlDriveability & Emissions Advanced Diagnostic Systems Power & PerformanceGraduates of UTI’s Automotive Technology program are well prepared to complete ASE examinations and can substitute their training for one year of the two years of work experience required to become ASE Certiied.And, you can take your training to a higher level by supplementing your core training program with Manufacturer-Speciic Advanced Training. Our industry relationships mean you have more opportunities to specialize your training and more connections when searching for a great career.21Not all programs are NATEF accredited. 2UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary. 3At the Rancho Cucamonga campus, the evening program is 68 weeks. 4At the Mooresville campus, the program is 485weeks. UTI graduates’ achievements may vary.We’ve had students who graduate and within a few short years are excitedly telling us they are Master Technicians or that they’ve been promoted to Shop Foreman and are now looking to hire their own techs.5Michael Heyman –BMW FastTrack Instructor, UTI OrlandoTo learn more about UTI’s automotive programs, visit UTI.edu/AutoUTI / AUTOMOTIVE TECHNICIAN TRAINING 05]]></page><page Index="8" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[POWER & PERFORMANCEWant to bring on the horsepower? Check out UTI’s Power & Performance courses that deliver special training in engine/vehicle modification, including blueprinting and design as well as dyno testing and verification. As part of UTI’s automotive technician training, you can learn how to rev up the speed and modify cars off the lot. Power & Performance courses are included in UTI’s core automotive program.*You’ll learn how to get the “biggest bang for the buck” and to optimize performance through modification. UTI’s Power & Performance courses meet the needs of the true performance enthusiast, covering everything from converters and camshafts to cylinder heads andnitrous oxide. Performance modifications will be put tothe test on a chassis dyno and engine dyno.And, get all the “tuning” skills you’ll need to perform vehicle modifications while keepingyour specs and emissionsstrictly street legal. Power & Performance also brings you up to speed in one of the fastest growing sectors in automotive technology: the personalization and performance enhancements of sport compact cars. You’ll get the lowdown on power adders — superchargers, turbochargers, cold air induction, nitrous, ignition and exhaust upgrades— and figure out how they perform during dyno testing.All of these skills will make you an even better technician — and more attractive to employers.**See it for yourself. Visit UTI.edu/PandP for more information.06 UTI / POWER & PERFORMANCE**UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.*Power & Performance courses are not part of the Automotive Technology Program at NASCAR Tech.]]></page><page Index="9" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Power & Performance courses teach you everything about an engine and finding the true magic behind making horsepower. You get to put together an engineand actually run that engine on a dyno. Hearing it run up to redline is exhilarating.Jesse Campbell – Power & Performance InstructorUTI / POWER & PERFORMANCE // 07]]></page><page Index="10" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[MANUFACTURER- SPECIFIC ADVANCED TRAININGThe best way to start your career faster, with better pay, and to become more attractive to potential employers.If you want to be best positioned for a careeryou’ll love, UTI’s Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training programs are the way to go. Employers want to hire technicians who are ready to work, and UTI’s factory-authorized training ensures that you train on the latest vehicles, tools and equipment supplied by the world’s best manufacturers. Many of these programs are not available at any other school, and our manufacturer relationships mean more career opportunities for you. We offer two different types of Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training programs:STUDENT PAIDOur student-paid programs are high-quality, exciting ways to learn about specific manufacturers and their vehicles. Adding Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training will increase your knowledge, make you more attractive to potential employers, and give you the opportunity to earn valuable credentials and certifications offered by the manufacturers.MANUFACTURER PAIDManufacturer-paid1 programs are top-level, specialized training programs that feature an advanced curriculum available to graduates of UTI’s core automotive and diesel programs. The best of the best at UTI are eligible to apply and be selected for manufacturer-paid training upon completion of core training. Because UTI is the industry’s choice for technician training, 4 out of every 5 students in manufacturer-paid training are UTI graduates.208 UTI / MANUFACTURER-SPECIFIC ADVANCED TRAININGOn average, graduates who have taken a Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training program are employed at a higher rate.3On average, graduates who have takena Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training program take less time to secure employment.3On average, graduates who have taken a Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training program receive a higher starting wage.31 MSATs may not be offered at all campuses and are subject to change. For information on campus locations, please visit UTI.edu.2 Admission is not guaranteed. To be eligible, students must successfully complete UTI’s core training program and meet certain Manufacturer-Specific Advanced Training terms and conditions. This program is offered by UTI’s Custom Training Group and is not part of UTI’s accreditation.3 Between June 1, 2013, and May 31, 2014, there were 356 total graduates from the BMW, International, Mercedes-Benz, MINI, Porsche and Volvo Manufacturer- Specific Advanced Training programs. Of these graduates, 307 were from Universal Technical Institute.4 Based on comparison with graduates from core programs between October 1, 2007, and September 30, 2012.f]]></page><page Index="11" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[BMWRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1995THE ADVANTAGESBMW’s partnership with UTI includes two great ways to get trained on some of the most precision- engineered vehicles being made today.BMW FASTTRACKFastTrack is 12 weeks of intensive BMW-speciic training on current models of some of the world’s most sophisticated driving machines, including the Z4, X3, X5, X6, 3, 5, 6 and 7 Series automobiles. You’ll learn the latest engine electronics on twin turbo, directinjection engines.This student-paid training sets you up for an accelerated career with BMW. Earn up to 7 factory credentials and achieve BMW Level IV technician status.BMW SERVICE TECHNICIAN EDUCATIONPROGRAM (STEP)The 20-week BMW manufacturer-paid program provides select UTI students with extensive training on BMW vehicles.BMW pays for the training to prepare graduates for jobs working at BMW franchised dealers.Graduates may earn up to 8 factory credentials and BMW Level III technician status.Your training is valued by BMW dealerships and independent repair shops nationwide. Student transcripts are loaded into BMW’s national technician database to ensure your training history is tracked and available to future employers.**UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.3,165+Number of technicians trained by UTI in the BMW STEP and FastTrack programsUTI has strong connections with manufacturers like BMW. Their training is completely up-to-date and I learned what I needed formy career.Kyle Plautz –Luxury Auto Mall of Sioux Falls UTI BMW STEP GradFor more information, visit UTI.edu/BMW UTI / BMW 09]]></page><page Index="12" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[FORD MOTOR COMPANYRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2000THE ADVANTAGESFORD ACCELERATED CREDENTIAL TRAINING (FACT)Ford FACT is student-paid training and is exclusive to UTI. It is 15 weeks of authorized Ford Motor Company technician training that gives you a great head start on a career with Ford Motor Company. Ford FACT graduates have the ability to earn 10 Ford STST classroom course credentials and 80 required web-based credentials in 9 Ford specialty certification areas. You’ll be on your way to Master Tech status far faster than those who don’t have this training up front.With STST credentials, graduates can become Ford Certified Specialists within the Ford and Lincoln dealer network.Also, students receive Ford Quick Service and Light Repair skills training and can earn Ford Quick Lane certification.The diagnostic, electrical and diesel training in Ford FACT is extremely comprehensive and will help you get an additional leg up on your career.21,000+Number of Ford FACT graduates trained by UTI$10 MILLION+Amount invested in Ford vehicles, tools, training aids and equipment in UTI training facilities across the countryI prefer the UTI students because they come in with the certifications that we need.*Ed Sovis –Service Manager, Jarrett Gordon FordYour training is valued by Ford and Lincoln dealerships nationwide. Students receive their own Ford STARS ID so their training history will be tracked and easily available to future employers.For more information, visit UTI.edu/Ford*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.f]]></page><page Index="13" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[The availability of qualified, trained automotive technicians is and will continue to be critical for GM. When looking at UTI’s industry leading curriculum, facilities, and student and employer support services, we knew we had a solid partner to support a growing need for technicians at our dealerships across the country.Mike Durkin –Director Dealer Service and Warranty Operations, General MotorsUTI / GENERAL MOTORS 11GENERAL MOTORSRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2013THE ADVANTAGESGM TECHNICIAN CAREER TRAININGUTI’s 12-week, student paid GM Technician Career Training prepares you for a career in one of GM’s 4,400 dealer locations.* As a technician in the GM Technician Career Training, you’ll experience a blended training program of online learning and hands-on training to diagnose, repair and maintain gasoline and diesel vehicles for the Chevrolet, Buick, GMC and Cadillac brands.When you participate in the GM Technician Career Training program, you’re getting skills and experience valued by every GM dealership. You can earn GM course credits that can elevate you to Bronze, Silver and Gold levels in multiple certiication areas upon graduation:11 GM instructor-led classroom course credits75 required web-based credits45 supplemental enrichment web-based credits4 Brand Lockup Vector File for Larger Scale applicationsFor more information, visit UTI.edu/GM *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.Medium Chevy logo minimum size:3.25” maximum size: 10” Released: 1.30.14GM DesignCorporate ID & Graphics20 MILLION+Number of GM vehicles on the road30,000+Number of technicians employed by GM in the United States alone]]></page><page Index="14" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[HONDA / ACURARELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2012THE ADVANTAGESHONDA PROFESSIONAL AUTOMOTIVE CAREER TRAINING (PACT)Honda PACT offers a concentrated training focus that gives you a quick head start on your career. In just 12 weeks, this student-paid program gives you the training most Honda techs would need 3 to 5 years to receive. Earn up to 11 Honda Certifications.Honda provides ongoing support for UTI’s advanced hands-on instruction. All course materials come directly from Honda, mirroring the learning environment at its training centers.Your training is valued by Honda and Acura dealerships nationwide.* Student transcripts are loaded into Honda’s national technician database to track student training history.For more information, visit UTI.edu/Honda13 MILLION+Honda and Acura vehicles on the road today, meaning strong employment opportunities*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.fff12 UTI / HONDA1,300+Honda/Acura dealerships across the US]]></page><page Index="15" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[MERCEDES-BENZRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1996THE ADVANTAGESUTI’s partnership with Mercedes-Benz includes two opportunities to perfect your skills on some of the world’s most supremely engineered automobiles. And, both programs are exclusive to UTI students.MERCEDES-BENZ ELITE STARTIn only 12 weeks, you can receive the credentials itwould take at least 3 years to earn through an authorized Mercedes-Benz dealer. Successful grads can gain technical training, skills and experience that are highly valued by Mercedes-Benz dealerships, making you extremely attractive to hiring managers.*In this student-paid program, you can train on the latest manufacturer systems and diagnostic equipment, including hands-on learning with the newest models: the S-Class, M-Class and E-Class.MERCEDES-BENZ ELITE ADVANCEDMercedes-Benz ELITE ADVANCED training is your fast path to an elevated position as a Certiied System Technician for Mercedes-Benz.During 24 weeks of intensive training at the MBUSA Learning & Performance Centers in Jacksonville, Florida, and Rancho Cucamonga, California, you will receive opportunities to earn multiple advanced factory certiications valued by Mercedes- Benz dealers nationwide.Successful candidates are selected by Mercedes-Benz. If chosen, your tuition is paid by Mercedes-Benz USA in return for an employment commitment after graduation.For more information, visit UTI.edu/Mercedes *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.UTI EXCLUSIVENo other schools ofer Mercedes-Benz ELITE START or ELITE ADVANCEDWe have seen a rapid increase inthe demand for technicians in the Mercedes-Benz dealer organization over the past couple of years. The demand far outstrips the supply of new talent available, presenting great opportunities for young men and women looking for a challenging and rewarding career.Gregory Settle – Manager,Learning & Performance Operations, Mercedes-Benz USAUTI GraduateUTI / MERCEDES-BENZ 13]]></page><page Index="16" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[fMINI is in the process of renovating many of our current facilities as well as adding new dealers to keep up with MINI’s growing units in operation.This will increase employment opportunities for MINI technicians by 50% over the next 5 years.*Robert Goodheart,MINI Dealer Development ManagerMINIRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2006THE ADVANTAGESMINI SERVICE TECHNICIAN EDUCATION PROGRAM (STEP)UTI’s MINI STEP program is one of our manufacturer- paid advanced training programs, offering students intensive training using the latest equipment to work on BMW’s unique MINI brand.Over 11 weeks, MINI students get hands-on experience with the most current models and MINI’s state-of-the- industry diagnostic, repair and maintenance equipment.MINI STEP training offers four factory credentials and qualifies you for MINI Level One Technician status, giving you a big boost in starting your career quickly working on these cutting-edge automobiles.For more information, visit UTI.edu/MINI 14 UTI / MINI*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.]]></page><page Index="17" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[NISSAN / INFINITIRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2006THE ADVANTAGESNISSAN AUTOMOTIVE TECHNICIAN TRAINING (NATT)UTI’s Nissan Automotive Technician Training gets you ready to work on the full line of the latest Nissan and Ininiti models, tools and technologies, including an introduction to the latest hybrid engines.Nissan has provided more than $1 million in vehicles and more than $500,000 in tools and equipment to UTI since 2006. The NATT program is greatly valued by Nissan and the transcripts of students are loaded into Nissan’s nationwide technician database to track training history.The 9-week, student-paid NATT program provides 60 percent of the Nissan course credits and requirements available to Nissan techs, preparing you to start your career immediately after graduation and making you more attractive to employers.* The program includes a strong electrical focus and other critical experiences that make you more marketable in the automotive industry.For more information, visit UTI.edu/Nissan *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.$1 MILLIONAmount of NATT scholarships Nissan has provided to UTI studentsDue to a double-digit increase in vehicle sales, Nissan and Infiniti dealers must recruit and attract new trained service technicians. UTI’s Nissan Automotive Technician Training (NATT) program is critical to filling our dealers’ hiring needs.John SpoonVice President, Aftersales Division Nissan North AmericaUTI / NISSAN 15]]></page><page Index="18" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[PORSCHERELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1999THE ADVANTAGESPORSCHE TECHNOLOGY APPRENTICESHIP PROGRAM (PTAP)UTI is the only school in America to offer Porsche’s PTAP training, an ultra-exclusive opportunity atthe company’s PCNA training centers in Atlanta, Georgia, and Easton, Pennsylvania. PTAP classes are limited to just 12 students — one of the best student-teacher ratios in the industry. Porsche directly supports, equips and invests in the UTI PTAP program, allowing students to receive training onall of Porsche’s world-class automobiles, tools and technologies, including the 911, Boxster, Panamera, Cayman and Cayenne.This exclusive 23-week, manufacturer-paid advanced training program accepts only the best of the bestfor extensive training, making graduates extremely attractive for technician careers at Porsche dealerships.*For more information, visit UTI.edu/PorscheONLY UTI-TRAINED TECHNICIANS ARE ACCEPTED INTO THE PORSCHE TECHNOLOGY APPRENTICESHIP PROGRAM96Number of factory credentials offered in the Porsche PTAP programf62%Percentage of technical courses available to professional Porsche technicians that are included in the PTAP program*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.16 UTI / PORSCHE]]></page><page Index="19" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[TOYOTA / LEXUS / SCIONRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2005THE ADVANTAGESTOYOTA PROFESSIONAL AUTOMOTIVE TECHNICIAN (TPAT)UTI’s 12-week, student-paid Toyota Professional Automotive Technician training prepares you for a career working in a Toyota, Lexus or Scion dealership.* Graduates earn 9 Toyota and 5 Lexus University of Toyota course credits upon completion of all program requirements.Students in the TPAT program receive focused training on Toyota, Lexus and Scion procedures, equipment and vehicles, including the Toyota Prius with its hybrid drive system. Students also receive their own Toyota SPIN training ID that tracks their Toyota and Lexus training history within the dealer network.Students are Toyota Maintenance Certiied duringthe training. They are also trained in Toyota Express Maintenance procedures. Program graduates can achieve Toyota Technician Expert status upon completion of all on-campus, post-campus and tenure requirements. This is the second tier in Toyota’s dealer network.For more information, visit UTI.edu/Toyota *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.NO. 1Toyota’s rank in hybrid sales in North AmericaUTI / TOYOTA 17$2.1 MILLIONAmount invested in Toyota training vehicles, tools and equipment on UTI TPAT campusesAs we grow, our dealers’ need for trained technicians grows ... Thisis a great time to get your foot in the door and build a career at Toyota.Rick Lester – Technician Development Manager, Technician Training and Education NetworkToyota Motor Sales USA Inc.]]></page><page Index="20" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[VOLVORELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1999THE ADVANTAGESVOLVO SERVICE AUTOMOTIVE FACTORY EDUCATION (SAFE) TRAININGVolvo SAFE is one of our manufacturer-paid advanced training programs. Volvo fully supports and invests in SAFE to ensure students are working on the latest models and equipment, including the XC70, XC90, S80, S60and C30.SAFE graduates are highly coveted by Volvo dealers, giving graduates a great jump start on a career working on Volvo’s exceptional vehicles.The Volvo SAFE program offers 12 factory credentials recognized at Volvo dealers around the country and student records are entered into Volvo’s national technician database.For more information, visit UTI.edu/VolvoNumber o5f Volvo models awarded top safety pick by the Institute for Highway Safety300+Number of Volvo dealerships nationwideUTI and the MSAT program definitely made it possible for me to get my job.* At this point, I’m living my dream.Logan Mathos – Volvo SAFE Graduate18 UTI / VOLVO*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.]]></page><page Index="21" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[AMSOIL ARENACROSS ARCADIRT LABDIRT MODIFIERS FORMULA DRIFT FORMULA ONEIHRAIMCAIRLLATE MODELMONSTER ENERGY SUPERCROSSMONSTER JAMNASA NASCARNASCAR CAMPING WORLD TRUCK SERIESMatt Ribesky, UTI Graduate Fox Sports 1 Cleatus*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.UTI / MOTORSPORTS INDUSTRY ALLIANCES 19MOTORSPORTS INDUSTRY ALLIANCESUTI maintains relationships with major players in the motorsports arena so you can have connections to this exciting industry!Want to work on a race team? Graduates have joined many racing series teams,* and our industry relationships mean more opportunities for you.Racing series and teams that have employed UTI, MMI or NASCAR Tech graduates:14Number of Sprint Cup team owners that have employed NASCAR Tech graduatesNASCAR K&N PRO SERIESNASCAR NATIONWIDE SERIESNASCAR SPRINT CUP SERIESNHRA SCHOLARSHIPS ROLEX GRAND-AM SERIESSCCASUPER LATE MODEL USA RACINGGrave Digger Scholarship Jeremy McGrath Scholarship Ricky Carmichael ScholarshipUTI.edu/scholarshipsMOTORSPORTS]]></page><page Index="22" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[TheONLYtraining in the country endorsed and sponsored by NASCARNASCARfff18 // UTI / NASCAR TECHNICIAN]]></page><page Index="23" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[NASCAR TECHNICIANTRAININGAT NASCAR TECHNICAL INSTITUTEOur NASCAR Technical Institute in Mooresville, North Carolina, is the exclusive educational provider of NASCAR technician training and an oicial partner of NASCAR.THE ADVANTAGESPut yourself to the test in the only training program in the country that’s sponsored and endorsed by NASCAR!*You’ll learn everything you need to know to work on a wide variety of vehicles as part of our Auto Technology training. Then, you can add NASCAR-speciic courses to learn motorsports fundamentals from high performance engines, fabrication and welding to aerodynamics and pit crew essentials. Through our elite Spec Engine program, select students have had the opportunity to build engines that competed in NASCAR-sanctioned races. Also, the instructors at NASCAR Tech bring impressive industry experience to our labs and classrooms.*NASCAR Tech cannot guarantee employment or salary.Modern racing takes more than just commitment. In today’s world, you have to get an education and know technology. I’m proud that my great- nephew graduated from NASCAR Tech, where he learned what he needs to find a niche and succeed in racing.Bobby Allison –Former NASCAR Winston Cup champion Named one of NASCAR’s 50 greatest driversTo learn more about NASCAR Technical Institute, visit UTI.edu/NASCARUTI / NASCAR TECHNICAL INSTITUTE 21]]></page><page Index="24" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[fDIESEL &INDUSTRIAL]]></page><page Index="25" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Diesel technicians are in high demand, and they’re rewarded with competitive pay and a variety of work environments. If you’re ready for a career working on some of the most powerful machines out there, UTI’s Diesel & Industrial Technology program is ready to work for you.ACCREDITEDUTI’s Diesel & Industrial Technology program is accredited by NATEF.1INDUSTRY RELATIONSHIPSCummins Freightliner International Peterbilt Western StarWhen it comes to learning how to work on some of the biggest engines out there, there’s no better choice than UTI. Our Diesel & Industrial Technology program has been chosen by the world’s top manufacturers to prepare you to work on everything from big trucks and corporate leets to farm equipment and oil rigs. The biggest names in diesel choose UTI’s graduates to keep their engines running.YOUR COURSES WILL INCLUDE:Diesel EnginesDiesel Fuel SystemsTruck Brakes & ChassisClimate ControlHydraulic Applications Electronic TechnologyTransport RefrigerationTruck Preventative Maintenance1Not all programs are NATEF accredited. 2At the Rancho Cucamonga campus, the evening program is 60 weeks. 3UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.DIESEL & INDUSTRIAL TECHNICIAN TRAININGCOURSE LENGTH: 45 WEEKSPROGRAM LOCATIONS: AZ, CA,2 IL, FL, MA, PA,TXIn UTI’s Diesel & Industrial Technology program, you’ll get hands-on training with powerful engines, including Caterpillar, Cummins, Daimler Trucks North America, Detroit Diesel, International and Peterbilt. Today’s diesel engines, commercial vehicles and heavy-equipment systems are highly sophisticated with advanced computer controls and electronic functions.TAKE3FOR MORE CAREER OPTIONSDo you want to open even more doors for endless opportunities throughout your career?3 UTI’s Auto/Diesel & Industrial Technology program combines all of the courses from our Automotive Technology program plus our Diesel & Industrial Technology program, allowing you to master each of these fields and increase your value to potential employers. For even more career options, consider adding Manufacturer- Specific Advanced Training on a particular line of vehicles.To learn more about UTI’s diesel programs, visit UTI.edu/DieselUTI / DIESEL TECHNICIAN TRAINING 23]]></page><page Index="26" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[1/3Cummins’ share of the market for heavy truck engines in North America12 WEEKSThe time it takes at UTI to earn Cummins Power Generation qualifications that would take a minimum of 3 to 5 years to earn in the fieldCUMMINSRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2006UTI offers two great programs as part of its partnership with Cummins. Students earn the same Cummins qualifications at UTI that are offered to technicians in the field at Cummins Training Facilities.CUMMINS ENGINES TRAININGUTI’s 12-week, student-paid Cummins Engines program provides you with an opportunity to learn on the latest engines and equipment. Cummins invests directly into UTI labs to ensure graduates are ready to work on the manufacturer’s exceptional line of diesel equipment. You can earn up to 10 Cummins qualifications, and graduates are able to do warranty work as soon as they start work at a Cummins Distributor or Authorized Dealer.*POWER GENERATION TRAININGIf you’d like to master the fundamentals of Cummins Power Generation, look no further than UTI’s Cummins Power Generation program. This 12-week, student-paid program focuses on equipment and controls, and engine maintenance of electrical generators and power generation systems that run in a variety of commercial and personal applications. Also, students have the opportunity toearn 8 Cummins Qualifications that will allow them to perform preventative maintenance on Cummins Power Generation equipment.For more information, visit UTI.edu/Cummins *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.ff24 UTI / CUMMINS]]></page><page Index="27" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[THE ADVANTAGESDAIMLER FINISH FIRST TRAININGDaimler’s Finish First training at UTI is a 12-week, student-paid program. Students who attend Finish First can earn valuable certiications that might have otherwise taken years to achieve, making them top choice technicians for the DTNA dealer network.Daimler actively invests in the Finish First curriculum. Students work on trucks that are rotated through the program to keep the technologies current and the vehicles up to date.Daimler’s Finish First includes the opportunity to work on some of the most popular brands of trucks on the road today, including the Freightliner and Western Star brands.Graduates qualify as Expert Level Technicians— Daimler’s highest ranking — with 7 valuable certiications that prepare them for great careers.For more information, visit UTI.edu/Daimler *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.DAIMLER TRUCKS NORTH AMERICA:FREIGHTLINER& WESTERN STARRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2008NO. 1Daimler Trucks North America’s rank as a heavy-duty truck manufacturer in North AmericaDaimler Trucks North America’s technician demand is large and growing. The DTNA Finish First Program at UTI provides our dealers with a steady flow of professional, entry-level technicians, trained with DTNA-specific curriculum and ready to hit the ground running when beginning work in the dealer network.*Juergen Steinhart – Senior Manager, Service Training Daimler Trucks North America, LLC.UTI / DAIMLER 25]]></page><page Index="28" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[700Number of International service locations throughout North America100,000+Number of trucks AND buses that Navistar produces each yearTHE ADVANTAGESINTERNATIONAL TECHNICIAN EDUCATION PROGRAM (ITEP)UTI offers ITEP as a 15-week, manufacturer- paid advanced training program, where elite UTI students can receive certifications in 11 factory training categories. Graduates are fully certified to perform warranty work based on their vehicle certifications, enabling them to get an immediate jump start to their careers.* The International ITEP program is highly valued by International dealers.UTI also offers a 6-week, student-paid International training program, where students can receive certifications in 6 factory training categories. The program teaches students about fleets, periodic maintenance, and electrical repair — some of the most state-of-the-industry instruction possible to prepare students fortheir careers.For more information, visit UTI.edu/International *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.fffNAVISTARINTERNATIONALRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2000The demand for medium & heavy truck technicians is now as high as it has ever been. With the constant change in emissions technology and complexity of electronic controls, dealers have been forced to look for more technicians with advanced skill sets. The programs at UTI prepare students to meet these growing challenges.John H. Koenig –Manager, Navistar Service Education Navistar Training Center26 UTI / INTERNATIONAL]]></page><page Index="29" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[PETERBILT TECHNICIAN INSTITUTEAs a Peterbilt Technician Institute (PTI) student, you’ll receive advanced training on the company’s products and technologies, including Peterbilt’s legendary trucks and the PACCAR MX-13 engine. The 12-week program will help you develop the manufacturer- speciic skills valued by Peterbilt’s more than 300 dealerships across North America.*To be accepted, each student must have a high GPA, stellar attendance and a clean motor vehicle record plus pass an entrance exam, drug test and interview. Graduates may need to relocate but pay no additional tuition to gain skills that set them apart in their ield.PETERBILT PROGRAM CERTIFICATIONS:101-Truck Fundamentals 200-HVAC203-Conventional Electrical 205-Hands-On Electrical205a-T/S Relay Circuits208 -Suspension222-PACCAR MX Certiication 223-MX-13 Powertrain Diagnostics 261a-Model 579 Service Training Peterbilt Software and ApplicationsFor more information, visit UTI.edu/PTI *UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.300+Number of Peterbilt dealerships across North AmericaPETERBILTTECHNICIANINSTITUTERELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2013Partnering with UTI will allow us to address the industry-wide shortage of qualified and certified Peterbilt service technicians. Our partnership will attract the next generation of Peterbilt technicians who will exceed expectations through exceptional service for our customers and their vehicles.Darrin SiverGeneral Manager Peterbilt Motors CompanyUTI / PETERBILT 27]]></page><page Index="30" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ffffCOLLISIONfffffffffffffff]]></page><page Index="31" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[COLLISION REPAIRCOURSE LENGTH: 45-54 WEEKSPROGRAM LOCATIONS: CA (Sacramento), TX (Houston)THE ADVANTAGESCOLLISION REPAIR AND REFINISHTECHNOLOGY TRAININGIf you are ready to reshape your future and enter a growing and recession-proof industry, UTI’s Collision Repair and Reinish Technology (CRRT) program is for you.* The core program and electives were developed in close partnership with I-CAR, the provider of collision repair training standards as deined by the industry, so you can graduate with the skills and experience you need to become an elite professional. Most insurance companies require repair work to be done by a technician with I-CAR certiications. At UTI you have the opportunity to receive many of these certiications upon graduation.INDUSTRY RELATIONSHIPSI-CAR // 3M // Axalta // Chief // SATA CCC // Lincoln Electric // Snap-onACCREDITEDUTI is accredited by NATEF, recognizing our Collision Repair program’s superiority.THE RECOGNITIONOpportunity to receive important I-CAR recognitions and certiicates, including:Intro to Collision CertiicateNon-Structural Technician (NST) ProLevel 1 Aluminum Structural Technician (AST) ProLevel 1 Steel Structural Technician (SST) ProLevel 1 Reinishing (REF) ProLevel 1Reinishing (REF) ProLevel 2Reinishing (REF) ProLevel 3Steel Welding CertiicateAluminum Welding CertiicateEstimating (EST) ProLevel 1Receive additional industry certiications in:Axalta Cromax Pro Certiied Reinisher Safety & Pollution Prevention (S/P2)3M Plastics and Composite Repair Systems Chief Velocity CertiicationEPA 609 A/C CertiicationLean Eiciency Certiicate*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.UTI’s CRRT program provides students with a solid foundation in collision repair training. Graduates from UTI will enter the marketplace with industry-recognized I-CAR ProLevel credentials, contributing to their career success.Bill Stage – Senior Director of Segment Development at I-CARTo learn more about UTI’s collision repair program, visit UTI.edu/CollisionUTI / COLLISION REPAIR 29]]></page><page Index="32" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[fMOTORCYCLEff]]></page><page Index="33" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[INDUSTRY RELATIONSHIPSBMW Motorrad Harley-Davidson Honda Kawasaki SuzukiYamahaYOUR COURSES WILL INCLUDE:Motorcycle Theory 1 & 2Engines, Power Flow & Precision Measuring Suspension & Chassis SystemsMachining Operations & Precision Measuring Electrical A – Design & OperationVehicle MaintenanceEngine Troubleshooting & Noise Diagnosis Performance Review TestingService Department OperationsAdvanced Electrical TestingDriveability / Performance TestingElective Program(s) on a Speciic BrandFOR OVER A DECADE, WE’VE TRAINED MORE TECHNICIANS TO WORK IN THIS INDUSTRY THAN ALL OTHER SCHOOLS COMBINED.For more about UTI’s Motorcycle Mechanics Institute, visit MMItech.edu*MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.MOTORCYCLE TECHNICIANTRAININGAT MOTORCYCLE MECHANICS INSTITUTEFor decades, MMI has been the industry’s top choice for motorcycle technicians. MMI ofers the experience you need to excel in an evolving industry that includes motorcycles, ATVs, personal watercraft, snowmobiles and more. If you’re ready to accelerate on your road to success, join the school that has more graduates working in the motorcycle industry than all other schools combined.*MMI’s 48 to 102 week training curriculumis designed to meet the needs of achanging industry. We work closely with the manufacturers to ensure you receive hands- on training using the most current motorcycle technology and equipment in state-of-the- industry training centers. And, you havemore opportunities to specialize your training and earn valuable factory certiications and credentials that are not available at any other school.The great thing about MMI is you’re not learning from a book but you’re learning from the bike... Employers light up once they hear that you’re from MMI.Ashley Katz – Technician, Precision V-TwinMMI GradUTI / MOTORCYCLE MECHANICS INSTITUTE 31]]></page><page Index="34" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ffffI landed my dream job, working at a well-known dealership that runs a race team and a machine shop. I learned everything I needed to become a tech at MMI, graduating on a Friday and starting my job the next Tuesday.*Brent Hopkins – Entry-Level Technician, BMW of San JoseMMI Grad*MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.BMW MOTORRADRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 2007THE ADVANTAGESMMI’s 12-week BMW Motorrad elective is fully endorsed by BMW Motorrad USA, with curriculum, instructors and facilities approved by BMW.The BMW Motorrad elective is equipped with the latest models and equipment to ensure our students are working on the most current motorcycles with the latest tools.The BMW Motorrad program makes graduates eligiblefor BMW Motorrad USA Level 1 Certified Motorcycle Technician Status, allowing graduates to immediately step into the field and begin an exciting career working on BMW motorcycles. You will receive training on the latest advanced BMW diagnostic test equipment, including the BMW Motorrad Online Service System (MOSS) PC.For more information, visit MMItech.edu/BMWMotorrad 32 UTI / BMW]]></page><page Index="35" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[HARLEY-DAVIDSONRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1984THE ADVANTAGESMMI is the only technician training school that ofers a Harley-Davidson speciic, 24-week elective curriculum that is aligned with Harley-Davidson University®.Students have the opportunity to acquire Harley-Davidson University® PHD course credit for Vehicle and Chassis Service and Electrical Diagnostics.MMI’s Harley-Davidson training is actively promoted by Harley-Davidson as its primary source for qualiied entry- level technicians.* The training includes the opportunity toqualify for advanced placement through the Harley-DavTechnician Recognition Program.Graduates are credited with 12 months of work experieviiddssoonnentoward Harley-Davidson’s ield recognition program upgraduation and employment in a Harley-Davidson® authorized dealership.For more information, visit MMItech.edu/Harley-Davidson *MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.eponconcen15,000+Number of Harley-Davidson graduates from MMI650+Number of Harley-Davidson® motorcycles available for student training at MMI campusesUTI / HARLEY-DAVIDSON 33]]></page><page Index="36" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[f477Number of Honda units at both MMI campuses combined, including on- and off-road motorcycles, ATVs and generators*MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.HONDA MOTORCYCLERELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1986THE ADVANTAGESHONDA HONTECHMMI is the only technical school that offers HonTech, a 24- week, Honda-authorized training program elective, which gives students the opportunity to complete Honda Dealer Training Certificates.Students have the opportunity to complete every Honda certification, including routine maintenance, advanced fuel induction and many other programs.Once all of these certifications are successfully completed, students earn Registered status with Honda, enabling them to begin their careers within the company’s dealership network.*For more information, visit MMItech.edu/Honda-HonTech 34 UTI / HONDA MOTORCYCLE]]></page><page Index="37" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[KAWASAKIRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1989THE ADVANTAGESKAWASAKI K-TECH SPECIALISTMMI’s exclusive Kawasaki K-Tech Specialist program, which is endorsed and supported directly by Kawasaki, includes a strong emphasis on hands-on training to prepare students for rewarding careers at Kawasaki dealerships.The 12-week program is unique because it encompasses all Kawasaki vehicles, including motorcycles, ATVs, utility vehicles, personal watercraft and recreation utility vehicles (gas and diesel).Kawasaki provides MMI’s K-Tech Specialist instructors with ongoing training to make sure they are teaching students the most current technologies. Graduates receive a Kawasaki-endorsed, entry-level technician certiicate, enabling them to start their careers right away.*For more information, visit MMItech.edu/Kawasaki *MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.6,000+Number of Kawasaki graduates trained by MMIUUTTII//KKAAWWAASSAAKKII//3353]]></page><page Index="38" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ffff1989The year MMI and Suzuki began the Suzuki FAST elective*MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.SUZUKIRELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1989THE ADVANTAGESFACTORY AUTHORIZED SUZUKI TRAINING (FAST)MMI’s exclusive Suzuki FAST training is a 12-week elective program with a curriculum developed in partnershipwith Suzuki Technical Support and updated regularly to incorporate the most recent technology.FAST students also have the ability to access all Suzuki ServicePRO® dealer training required to achieve Bronze Technician Recognition level. Graduates receive six months of tenure credit toward their Bronze-level certification, cutting the amount of time required to become certified in half.FAST students graduate with solid shop experience, MMI training and a leg up on achieving Suzuki Bronze certification and eligibility for an exciting career working on Suzuki motorcycles.*For more information, visit MMItech.edu/Suzuki 36 UTI / SUZUKI]]></page><page Index="39" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[YAMAHARELATIONSHIP BEGAN: 1989THE ADVANTAGESYAMAHA YAMAPRO® TRAININGMMI’s exclusive 12-week YamaPro® elective training is oicially endorsed by Yamaha. The curriculum is developed by MMI with support and assistance from Yamaha, and Yamaha reviews the program’s instructors and facilities.Students learn to repair a variety of Yamaha vehicles, including street/sport bikes, of-road bikes, ATVs, RUVs, PWCs, snowmobiles and generators.YamaPro® students also have the opportunity to earn Yamaha Technical Academy (YTA) Bronze-level and Silver-level Technician Certiication — providing a distinct advantage for entry-level technicians beginning their careers.*For more information, visit MMItech.edu/Yamaha*MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.6,500+Number of Yamaha graduates trained by MMIUTI / YAMAHA 37]]></page><page Index="40" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[MARINEf]]></page><page Index="41" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Along with the core marine training, MMI students enjoy specialized training for Honda Marine, Mercury Marine, Suzuki Marine, Volvo Penta, and Yamaha Marine. Each 3-week, manufacturer-speciic course is designedto provide students with the knowledge and experience required to work in marinas, boat yards, marine dealers or wherever your life on the water may take you.INDUSTRY RELATIONSHIPSHonda Marine Mercury Marine Suzuki Marine Volvo Penta Yamaha MarineYOUR COURSES WILL INCLUDE:EnginesLower Units/Outdrives RiggingService OperationsFuel & Lubrication Systems Electrical SystemsDiesel 1 & 2Volvo PentaHonda MarineYamahaSuzukiMercTech 1 & 2CapstoneMARINE MECHANICS INSTITUTE HAS MORE GRADUATES WORKING IN THE INDUSTRY THAN ANY OTHER SCHOOL.To learn more about UTI’s Marine Mechanics Institute, visit UTI.edu/Marine*MMI cannot guarantee employment or salary.MARINE TECHNICIANTRAININGAT MARINE MECHANICS INSTITUTEIf you love the water and are in search of a great career, you belong at Marine Mechanics Institute (MMI). The 51-week, industry-aligned curriculum emphasizes the real-world skills needed by marine dealerships. Througha combination of classroom instruction, demonstrations and hands-on work in the lab, you’ll diagnose, service and repair marine mechanical systems using current technology and equipment.You’ll have the opportunity to work hands-on with some of the best marine brands in the world, including everything from inboard gas and diesel engines to outboard 2-stroke and 4-stroke motors.At MMI, the student learns all different brands of motors. They learn factory training, which is very important, and they’ve got access to the latest technology. We hire almost exclusively MMI students* and I’m advising my kids togo to MMI.Bob Leatherman – Owner, Boat TuneOrlando, FloridaUTI / MARINE MECHANICS INSTITUTE 39]]></page><page Index="42" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[GET TRAINED TO JOIN AN INDUSTRY ON THE MOVE.DEMAND IS GROWING FOR PROFESSIONAL ENTRY-LEVEL TECHNICIANS AND UNIVERSAL TECHNICAL INSTITUTE IS LEADING THE WAY TO MEET OUR INDUSTRY PARTNERS’ NEEDS.Cars today have more computer-processing power than the spacecraft that landed on the moon. There are cars that can park themselves and keys that can be programmed to control maximum speed, stereo volume and more.The technician of today doesn’t just work with tools. The transportation industry is changing. It’s becoming more technology-based and reliant on computers and innovation. Everyone relies on transportation and we all need professionally-trained technicians to keep our vehicles running.*UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.CAREERSUTI training means opportunity. You can chart your own career that includes any number of exciting opportunities,* such as:Automotive Technician Diesel Technician Motorcycle Technician Marine Technician Collision Specialist Master Technician Service WriterService Advisor Service Manager PainterInsurance Adjustor Repair Estimator Shop Foreman Fleet Manager Parts Manager General Manager Dealership Owner Technical Instructor40 UTI / READY TO WORK]]></page><page Index="43" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[UTI GETS YOU READY TO WORKThe highest-quality training on the industry’s leading brands by expert instructors with real world experience and the career support youneed to succeedEMPLOYMENT SERVICESWe have local employment specialists available at each campus to helpyou succeed while you’re in school and after graduation.* And, we havea centralized team that specializes in sourcing graduate jobs and building national relationships with dealers, distributors and other large employers across the country.OUR SERVICES INCLUDE:Part-time employment assistance during schoolProfessional résumé development Interview trainingNationwide job database On-campus interviewsCareer development classes On-campus career fairs & recruitmentTo learn more about our Student Support Services, visit UTI.edu/employment* UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.EMPLOYERS NEED TECHNICIANSTo help attract and retain the best technicians, many employers are offering incentive packages to Universal Technical Institute (UTI) graduates in addition to standard wage and benefit packages.**The number of incentive programs available continues to grow as the demand for technicians increases. More of UTI’s employer partners are implementing these programs because they need to fill positions and they tell us they prefer to hire UTI grads.EXAMPLES OF INCENTIVESOFFERED INCLUDE:Tuition Reimbursement Incentive Programs (TRIP) – Some employers will help you pay back your student loans after graduation. Tool purchase assistanceRelocation assistance Sign-on bonusesTalk to your Representative to learn more about the programs available in your area.**Incentive programs and employee eligibility are at the discretion of the employer and available at select locations. Special conditions may apply. For a complete list of programs available, ask your representative.UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.]]></page><page Index="44" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ff®Prior to graduation, eligible students will receive a voucher that can be redeemed for a Career Starter Tool Set.* Also, you will have access to tool discounts through the Snap-on Student Excellence Program as long as you are attending classes at UTI full time.YOUR BEST CHOICEAt UTI, you choose your career path. We’ll help you make it happen through training that’s designed to provide the technical and professional skills that can lead to success. What makes UTI the best choice for you?EMPLOYMENTAs a UTI grad, you’re ready to work. We actively help you start your career after graduation. In fact, 4 of 5 UTI grads find employment in their fields of study.**RELATIONSHIPSUTI is chosen by industry and we have relationships with the world’s top manufacturer brands. From our training curriculum, equipment and vehicles to employment assistance after graduation, we use our connections to help you succeed in your career.SKILLS TO SUCCEEDBecause UTI is committed to providing students with the skills necessary to succeed in the 21st century, we support the STEM Education Coalition and ensure necessary science, technology, engineering and math skills are included in our curriculum. Additionally, we work closely with professional school counselors and support the American School Counselor Association (ASCA).ACCREDITATIONUTI is accredited by the Accrediting Commission of Career Schools and Colleges (ACCSC), a recognized accrediting agency by the U.S. Department of Education. This ensures you have a quality education and the best opportunity for success. How?+ ACCSC regularly conducts site visits to ensure we are meeting students’ needs and adhering to strict guidelines regarding ethical and honest practices. It also confirms our schools provide a safe learning environment and the best opportunity for your success.+ If you plan to apply for federal funded school loans, it is important that the school you choose is accredited by a recognized agency. Only accredited schools are eligible for federal funding.As the nation’s leading provider of technician training in the automotive, diesel, motorcycle and marine industries, our true measure of success is the success of our graduates. ACCSC accreditation is one way we can better position you for success.*Students who are near graduation who have no outstanding obligations to the school and have not previously taken part in a tool voucher program on any UTI/MMI/NASCAR Tech affiliated campus are eligible to participate in the UTI Tool Voucher Program. **Approximately 9,900 of the 10,600 UTI graduates in 2013 were available for employment. At the time of reporting, approximately 8,700 were employed within one year of their graduation date, for a total of 88%. UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary.]]></page><page Index="45" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[SCHOLARSHIPSMAKING EDUCATION MORE AFFORDABLEWe continue to make available a scholarship fund for eligible enrolled students pursuing technician training with Universal Technical Institute, Motorcycle Mechanics Institute, Marine Mechanics Institute and NASCAR Technical Institute to support the growing demand for professional technicians in the transportation industry. With the Industry’s Choice Scholarship program, UTI has made more than $15 million in scholarships available for 2015* to help our students become ready to work.In addition to the funds that UTI makes available for our students, the UTI Foundation has scholarships available and there are many other scholarship opportunities available that can apply to your training.Visit UTI.edu/scholarships to learn more about scholarship opportunities and how to make your education more afordable.* Scholarships available to those who qualify. Speciic conditions, criteria and awards vary by state.UTI really put my life into motion and I don’t think I would be where IamandashappyasIamright now without their help... It’s my career, it’s my life, and I’ve dropped everything for it and I’m so glad I did. And thanks to them, I’m living out my dream.Kenna Primm –Marketing Communications Coordinator Roush Yates EnginesBrienne Davis Scholarship Recipient$15 MILLIONThe amount of money in scholarships UTI has made available to students for 2015UTI / SCHOLARSHIPS 43]]></page><page Index="46" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[THE SUPPORT YOU NEED TO SUCCEEDFINANCIAL ASSISTANCEFinancial aid available to those who qualifyUTI participates in the federal Title IV programs (grants and loans) as well as various state programs Private financing also availableSCHOLARSHIPSVisit UTI.edu/scholarships to learn more about scholarship opportunities1 and how to make your education more affordable.UTI FOUNDATIONScholarship fund provides full or partial scholarships toassist students who would not otherwise be able to complete their educationStudent Pantry and Student Emergency Fund help students stay in school by providing a food bank for students as well as financial grants to cover unexpected emergenciesAdvanced Training Scholarship assists with relocation costs for students seeking additional manufacturer-specific trainingEMPLOYMENT SERVICESPart-time employment2 assistance during school Graduate employment services available Professional résumé and interview training availableHOUSING SERVICESAssistance finding housing during school Roommate matchingGuidance on suitable housingTUITION REIMBURSEMENT INCENTIVEPROGRAM (TRIP)Some companies offer to pay graduates’ loans through TRIP3 Program helps participating companies attract and retain top techniciansALUMNI ASSOCIATIONNetworking opportunitiesJob boards and résumé building tools Member discountsAvailable at Connect.UTI.edu1Scholarships available to those who qualify. Specific conditions, criteria and awards vary by state. 2UTI cannot guarantee employment or salary. 3Incentive programs and employee eligibility are at thediscretion of the employer and available at select locations. Special conditions may apply. For a complete list of programs available, ask your representative.44 UTI / STUDENT SUPPORT SERVICES / FAQSFREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONSThese are some of the questions we often hear from potential students, parents, teachers and counselors:Does UTI help students find work while attending school?Yes, our local Employment Specialists at each campus are there to help you succeed. We’ll assist you with your search for a part-time, local job that won’t interfere with your studies but will help cover your living expenses.Does UTI help students secure employment upon graduation?Yes, our team of Employment Specialists will work very hard to connect youwith employers upon graduation. Our industry relationships and manufacturer programs have allowed us to builda nationwide network of companies looking to hire our graduates. While employment cannot be guaranteed, we do our best to ensure UTI graduates are employed in their fields of study upon graduation. Services are also available to graduates and alumni through access to our alumni community, UTI Connect (Connect.UTI.edu).Is there safe and affordable housing near UTI campuses?Yes, we pre-screen and work closely with local apartment communities close to our campuses to ensure you have safe and affordable options. We also provide roommate matching services if you would like to share expenses with other students.Does UTI provide any support after graduation?Yes, our graduates can take lifetime refresher courses for previously passed classes (if still offered) and automatically become members of the alumni association UTI Connect, which provides access to networking opportunities, job boards and résumé building tools. Our Employment Services team is also available to help with your career after graduation.]]></page><page Index="47" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[UTI-Avondale – AZ800-859-1202MMI-Phoenix – AZ800-528-7995UTI-Rancho Cucamonga – CA 888-692-7800UTI-Sacramento – CA877-884-2254UTI/MMI-Orlando – FL866-821-3810UTI-Lisle – IL800-441-4248UTI-Norwood – MA866-753-6553NASCAR Tech – NC UTI-Mooresville Location 866-316-2722UTI-Exton – PA877-884-3986UTI-Dallas – TX877-873-1083UTI-Houston – TX800-325-0354AUTOMOTIVE MOTORCYCLE MARINEDIESELCOLLISION REPAIR NASCARUTI has a national reputation for excellence with 11 campus locations across the country and employer contacts nationwide.ARE YOU READY?If you are willing to build your career with your own two hands and have a desire to train with the best, it’s time to get you ready for work. For more information on how UTI training can prepare you for a career you’ll really love, contact us.Phone: 800-331-2978 Web: UTI.eduE-mail: info@uti.eduwww.facebook.com/UTI www.twitter.com/UTITweet www.youtube.com/UTIVision]]></page><page Index="48" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[CHOSEN BY INDUSTRY. READY TO WORK.Visit UTI.edu Visit UTI.eduFor more information about our graduation rates, the median debt of students who completed theItem #991888 Rev 08/13 Item #991888 // Rev 3/15program and other important information, please visit our website at www.uti.edu/disclosure. For information about our graduation rates, the median debt of students who completed the program and other important information, visit our website at www.uti.edu/disclosure.]]></page></pages></Search>